<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Ty Pozzobon Foundation</title>
    <link>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Ty Pozzobon Foundation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 10:21:02 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.typozzobon.com/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranchman’s event raises awareness, money for Ty Pozzobon Foundation</title>
      <link>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/ranchmans-event-raises-awareness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 10:21:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/ranchmans-event-raises-awareness/</guid>
      <description>CALGARY, Alberta – When Ty Pozzobon died earlier this year, he left family and friends searching for answers.
They hope to find them through the Ty Pozzobon Foundation, which was established a few weeks after his death to protect and support the health and well-being of rodeo competitors inside and outside the arena. As the foundation tries to build, it continues to search for funds.
That’s where the Ranchman’s Renegade Charity PBR Bullbustin’ came in last week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Ty Pozzobon Foundation</title>
      <link>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/announcing-the-ty-pozzobon-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 15:55:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/announcing-the-ty-pozzobon-foundation/</guid>
      <description>CALGARY, Alberta &amp;ndash; Shortly over a month after the passing of Ty Pozzobon, family and friends close to Pozzobon are proud to announce the Ty Pozzobon Foundation (TPF).
In the first meetings, the Foundation mission statement has been set forth: &amp;ldquo;To protect and support the health and well-being of rodeo competitors inside and outside the arena.&amp;rdquo;
Pozzobon&amp;rsquo;s best friend, Tanner Byrne stepped forward as the spokesperson of Ty&amp;rsquo;s foundation.
&amp;ldquo;We knew we wanted to all do something for Ty in his name to make a positive change in our sport,&amp;rdquo; said Byrne.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>