<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Ty Pozzobon Foundation</title>
    <link>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Ty Pozzobon Foundation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 20:34:39 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.typozzobon.com/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ty Pozzobon Foundation Launches Series of Educational Videos</title>
      <link>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/ty-pozzobon-foundation-launches-series-of-educational-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 20:34:39 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/ty-pozzobon-foundation-launches-series-of-educational-videos/</guid>
      <description>The Ty Pozzobon Foundation, in partnership with the Canadian Pro Rodeo Sports Medicine Team, has launched the first video, addressing concussion awareness, of a planned multi-part series in a continued effort to promote the health and well-being of Western Sports athletes. Release Date: July 17, 2018
CALGARY, Alberta – In a continued effort to protect and support the health and well-being of rodeo competitors inside and outside the arena, the Ty Pozzobon Foundation and the Canadian Pro Rodeo Sports Medicine Team (CPRSMT) announced their latest initiative Thursday night, proudly unveiling the first of a series of educational videos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpha Bull Making a Difference</title>
      <link>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/alpha-bull-making-a-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 13:59:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/alpha-bull-making-a-difference/</guid>
      <description>Besplug’s events raising money, awareness for Ty Pozzobon Foundation Release Date: March 16, 2018
When Ty Pozzobon died 14 months ago, those closest to him decided quickly to honor him.
The Ty Pozzobon Foundation was created last March to “protect and support the health and well-being of rodeo competitors inside and outside the arena.” That’s the foundation’s mission, and those involved have been developing the ideas necessary to raise funds toward it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional bull rider Ty Pozzobon diagnosed with CTE</title>
      <link>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/professional-bull-rider-ty-pozzobon-diagnosed-with-cte/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 17:29:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/professional-bull-rider-ty-pozzobon-diagnosed-with-cte/</guid>
      <description>October 10, 2017
Media Contact: Susan Gregg, UW Medicine, sghanson@uw.edu; 206-616-6730
  The Pozzobon family is not participating in media interviews at this time. If you wish to speak to Drs. Keene or MacDonald, please contact Susan Gregg.
  Ty Pozzobon, a 25-year-old professional bull rider from Merritt, British Columbia, Canada died January 9, 2017, from suicide.
Pozzobon’s family suspected that his death was the result of repeated head injuries and concussions sustained during his rodeo career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranchman’s event raises awareness, money for Ty Pozzobon Foundation</title>
      <link>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/ranchmans-event-raises-awareness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 10:21:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/ranchmans-event-raises-awareness/</guid>
      <description>CALGARY, Alberta – When Ty Pozzobon died earlier this year, he left family and friends searching for answers.
They hope to find them through the Ty Pozzobon Foundation, which was established a few weeks after his death to protect and support the health and well-being of rodeo competitors inside and outside the arena. As the foundation tries to build, it continues to search for funds.
That’s where the Ranchman’s Renegade Charity PBR Bullbustin’ came in last week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Ty Pozzobon Foundation</title>
      <link>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/announcing-the-ty-pozzobon-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 15:55:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.typozzobon.com/news/announcing-the-ty-pozzobon-foundation/</guid>
      <description>CALGARY, Alberta &amp;ndash; Shortly over a month after the passing of Ty Pozzobon, family and friends close to Pozzobon are proud to announce the Ty Pozzobon Foundation (TPF).
In the first meetings, the Foundation mission statement has been set forth: &amp;ldquo;To protect and support the health and well-being of rodeo competitors inside and outside the arena.&amp;rdquo;
Pozzobon&amp;rsquo;s best friend, Tanner Byrne stepped forward as the spokesperson of Ty&amp;rsquo;s foundation.
&amp;ldquo;We knew we wanted to all do something for Ty in his name to make a positive change in our sport,&amp;rdquo; said Byrne.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>